hello hello hello
and bring up the chat on my phone
because i think we're gonna need the
full
monitor for this stream
i think it like takes a little bit to
propagate and that's why
i find this ui so confusing
so there's another way to get to my chat
on here my channel
and then i go to videos no
i can click live here and that works
first
hi perfect hello people
what's up what's
all up cool we live boys
we live let's go let's go yo
let's get let's see how many people we
got all right so first we're gonna have
to make a decision
and we're gonna listen to a song
looks like we have some relatively low
tier
questions and comments
um in here
i did watch some landing congratulations
so now that we're done with the bagel
we're going to be doing write you a
scheme version 2.0
now i did version 1.0 a long time ago
and
i do want to give one note um
on the last stream
uh i read the comments briefly and
i think it's kind of a
tragedy that we can't trust any
institutions anymore
um it's sad that that all of the
uh universities journalistic
political these institutions are just
so unequipped um to deal with the modern
world
and they are not adapting well
so like paul graham said
i'm excited for the people who are going
to come in and build new institutions
um it's not that way not to trust them
it's just that i don't respect them
you know i don't respect i don't want
the new york times to say good things
about me i don't respect the new york
times
i don't want an honorary degree from
yale university i don't respect yale
university
who do i respect a bunch of random
people on the internet
satoshi nakamoto
vitalik eliezer yukowski scott alexander
scott aaronson curtis yarvin
uh paul graham um
you know it's it's a smattering of
individuals elon musk who can be trusted
and i think are adapting to the modern
world in an okay way
while these institutions remain so
incredibly tone deaf
uh to the fact that we're not interested
in being lied to anymore
all right
i also the only other comment i'm going
to respond to
is non-constructive proof
um there's a stack overflow if somebody
can link that to me
um if somebody can link that to me i
will go over that proof
because i realized that i didn't go over
the proof uh at all i just kind of
glossed over it and once i understood it
and then i realized that i actually
didn't
understand it totally the way that i
thought i did so if somebody could link
to that proof
um
this is the desert identity right
thank you hype train um
does someone want to uh
want to link to that i know it's in the
comment but we don't get youtube
comments anymore
uh there's no more youtube comments in
my browser they went away
i did make decent revenue from the last
stream i did um
so if nobody's gonna link to it then um
not here um so
r uh equals the square root of n
is integral uh if rational uh
for n uh exists in it so
what you're trying to show here is that
if
r is a rational number it has to be
a integral number so
we start with okay so r is some fraction
a over b
um the greatest common divisor of a b at
one which means it's a reduced fraction
and then this is the bayesian identity
this is something that has to be true
now if you'll notice this jump to the
next step
um so if you look here uh a
minus br times c plus dr if you take
a over b and you substitute it in here
uh the b's cancel out so you're left
with a minus a which is zero
so it's zero times uh c dr which
obviously equals zero
um and then you can take
uh this
um and you guys should remember foil
from algebra to multiply your firsts um
your inners uh your outers
so that's plus dra and then your lasts
which is brdr but actually you'll notice
r times r um is defined
to be n all right so we can actually
just change that to bdn
um so we're left with ac
minus bdm uh
minus brc minus dra
so we can factor an r out of here
um let's let's just flip these around
all right it's the same
um so we can factor an r out of this
uh d a minus bc
but we know that da minus bc equals one
so we're left with replace that with one
and we're left with uh
what's written here now ac
well considering b and c are obviously
integers
c is also an integer so this is an
integer
this has to be an integer obviously n n
is an integer it's
defined to be a natural number so
because these are both integers
and we know zero is an integer i mean
another way we can just write this
is zero equals b d n minus r equals v
minus a c
right so uh
uh so yeah i did promise it was a noob
stream so we're gonna we're gonna go
through and be nice
to people like that
george made up all sorts of in the
last stream
he's fooling you guys just because he
cost confidently about fields he does
not know as much as programming
what's wrong
do you have a counter example to
anything that i said
um and you know what i'm gonna make i'm
gonna make a claim i'm gonna make a
claim here
the time traveler 253 come forward right
now with a counter example or you're
banned from the stream for life
give this guy 10 seconds
20 seconds come on come on
come forward you have people who talk
like this and they talk like oh i am so
clever he said a lot of wrong things but
then they don't have any specifics at
all
all right i'll review the stream and
write down some examples okay i'll uh
you know you can you can reply in the
comments but now you're banned
um right because you don't have any
examples you honestly don't
what you don't like is a feeling like if
you had like three things like you want
to come at me with those things i'm
happy to have a conversation
but if you're gonna be like oh well he
said a lot of wrong things
because they didn't make me happy and
things that don't make me happy are
wrong
you get banned
okay um so
we're gonna do this oh also
the other thing that i wanted to talk
about was i found a bug
in my busy beaver code and it wasn't
producing
i shouldn't have been lazy you guys
shouldn't let me uh
get away with with laziness
so this is from the busy beaver streams
where i implemented
the zany zoo paper um
so you shouldn't be allowed to i
shouldn't have gotten away with being
like oh i know what's right even though
my numbers don't match
if your numbers don't match the paper
you are
95 of the chance you're wrong maybe five
percent chance the paper is wrong if
you've really looked over it
but um of course we're in the 95 bucket
i had a bug
so these are the number of states that
we should be generating
uh for the given sizes in their tree
normal form
so this has been pushed to github
if you go in
36 for two by two
three five zero eight for three by two
two seven six four for two by three
one of my biggest mistakes was this
when i added in these other states even
though they're overwritten later on
i didn't make a copy of the machine and
not making a copy of the machine
caused these num states and num symbols
to be incremented erroneously so once i
made a copy a lot of that bugs were
fixed now
i'm still not getting a perfect match
for four and two
so i wonder if i still have a bug um
this one is giving me five one one one
six two uh do two and four
i think this one gives me three four two
five
thirty two and they're very close um so
one of the things i found
was i set this bound on the number of
steps to 200
if i change it to 100
i get a perfect match with paper
but when i change it back to 200 which
is what they claimed in the paper i
didn't get a perfect match
so i'm not exactly sure what's going on
here but it's nice to see my numbers be
a whole lot closer to the papers
you aren't done until you've matched the
paper perfectly
of course i'm still not done because i
haven't matched the paper perfectly but
remember when they claimed that the 5x2
machine was getting this many
my implementation got this when we ran
it over on the server
now i got this so uh that's at least a
whole lot
closer to what the paper said
uh you created a copy before but you
deleted yeah maybe
maybe because i thought like it didn't
matter uh
because i was like oh i overwrite it but
i forgot that all these things have side
effects
but we will program in a language where
there are no side effects
in haskell and i think this is an
appropriate
um stream
so scheme is a programming language
we're going to be writing a scheme
interpreter in haskell that gets you
kind of to what the truth uh programming
languages are
i want to talk about one other comment
that i read it was like george
could you please uh give us a tutorial
where you tell us what your terminal
setup is and what computer you have
these kind of things only matter to
people who like to circle jerk
they do not have anything to do with
skill uh so if any time
two things that i want everybody in the
comments to dog pile
i want them to dog pile people asking
about like frivolous
things like that and i want to you all
to dogpile concerned trolls
and uh tell them that i don't give a
about their concerns
um and you know my brand and all that
and you know they can uh
they can get and then the uh oh
the wokeness police
uh the the only solution for the
wokeness police is
absolute and complete ridicule
uh so yeah i mean that one that one
ridicule is always ridiculous always a
good oh they're coming for you man the
wokeness please
you heard of the boogeyman you heard of
the boogaloo oh they're coming for you
uh so that's yeah uh
level two hype train thank you thank you
um
what toothpaste
um this guy's a vip so we're gonna
listen really to what he has to say
is there some fundamental cs topic that
you can teach people they wouldn't be
able to teach themselves
oh that's another kind of thing that i
was thinking um
it's very hard for me to teach like this
um it's very hard for me to teach
like okay the twitch comments are twitch
comments from from hundreds of random
people are not really a good uh
audience for lectures one of the things
that i think that would work a lot
better
is if we brought one person onto the
stream and taught them a specific
topic and then if you really want to
teach somebody something
i think the best way to do is kind of
socratic method style
right you make sure you check their
understanding at every step
um because a lot of times when you're
learning something
uh you don't know what you don't know
and then by
being being asked to do something and
realize i remember i remember being in
third grade
and um my uh
it was in second grade second grade and
they were they were
going to put me up a grade for math and
i spoke with the third grade teacher
and she asked me george do you know your
multiplication tables
um and uh i said yes
and then she asked me some questions she
asked what's 6 times 6 and i said 36
and she asked me what's 8 times 8 and i
said 64.
and then she asked me what 6 times 8 and
i didn't know 6 times 8
because i actually just knew the squares
i didn't actually know i didn't know
that you could multiply besides
multiplying numbers by itself
um so uh yeah
yeah we could potentially take vips we
could also potentially say it's like 100
for 30 minutes uh might be another
option
so we can either charge money or we can
have a merit-based
thing uh those are the two things that
it is acceptable
to discriminate upon in a modern society
you can discriminate based on
uh paying money or you can discriminate
based on skill
don't charge you'll get banned from
twitch you guys are always so
like don't do x don't do y you'll get
banned from twitch
well i could get big twitch if twitch
bans me twitch bans me man
like i'm not gonna i'm not gonna go out
of my way to violate any rules but if i
can't do what i think is like
normal things to do then all right i'm
banned from twitch i'll go stream
somewhere else you know
all you do is criticize everything we
say brah
uh i don't even know how to respond to
that
yeah i don't know about making your own
stream server i think there's another
one
um do we have to ban someone yeah always
always be
yeah i know i can show my earnings but
you know it's tacky
um we'll stream on a voice app
if i die i die that's right
that's the philosophy lanalocks
thank you for bringing your people in
and i think that is a perfect time
to actually get started on the stream
okay
although the majority of modern
programming files see algo style lifts
lisp syntax is simple using the same
syntax to represent code and data the
list
this is called homo iconicity i didn't
know that
if a program written in it can be
manipulated as data using the language
such the pro i don't know i mean python
has like an ast import ast
um a scheme a dialective lisp is pretty
straightforward we won't follow the
strict
scheme standard for stake of brevity but
aim to include many useful features
why haskell because this guy loves
haskell okay that's good to know
um what are we gonna do we're gonna make
a very basic but robust programming
language that is both simple to use
and highly extendable is that how you
spell that word i don't think that's how
you spell that word
no it has an a um
so this is some basics of lisp uh
understanding check what form does
scheme use to represent data
um the same one that it uses for code oh
man i should have paid more attention
how would you create a function lambdas
you can use lets for setting variables
scheme is a dynamically typed
interpreted functional language
c is a statically typed compiled
imperative language
yeah can you rearrange lead expressions
into lambda
i don't think so you can definitely put
lambdas into lets
um write out an explanation and
example that demonstrates using lexical
scope while the
things are only scoped when they're
inside the lambda so i think most of
those answers questions or answers are
right but some of them are probably
wrong
you guys can make fun of me in the
comments
um
before we start there's a note i have to
make before we start i'm going to take
a time to complain about string
um
uses overloaded strings and all files so
i advocate
text this is the strong position on text
i don't know i'm already questioning
this tutorial
um from from a word being spelled wrong
now we're gonna we're gonna go with it i
believe in this tutorial after much ado
here's the remnants of the
representation of the s expression from
lisp val
all coded data is represented by one of
the following data constructors
there's nothing else take a look
okay so let's write that out so we have
data which is a list val
which is creating a
oh i really i'm gonna have to do that
that text thing or it's not gonna be
happy
language overloaded strings okay atom
is a t dot text so if i remember my
haskell syntax
correctly this is the
name of the type and this is the
underlying haskell type
uh and then it can have multiple uh
types and that's why this is kind of
like an or for types
so damn critical listen bro
it's about having standards and that's
why
you're banned
right now it's not about i like to be
criticized too i like to be criticized
precisely
and exactly you know ironically your use
of sodium critical
is a vague imprecise criticism
the type that gets you banned but
precise constructive criticism is great
um string is a t
text fun is an eye funk is that a
haskell type
i guess it has to be
what's an l funk
from iphone i don't know we'll see if it
compiles
um lambda ifunk
mctx well now i just don't know what i'm
doing i'm just typing
we all know what a nil type is and then
bool bool
deriving
typable data oh
now here we define ifunk
iphone call i don't really know what all
this does
hopefully we'll figure it out
all right here we go bull number and
string are trivial wrappers for haskell
values nil is the null type
atom represents variables to represent
an
s expression let's just look into
exactly what an s expression is
um
symbolic expressions are a notation for
a nested list restructured data
so s expressions which contain cycles i
guess they can contain
cycles
okay cool
evaluation method
oh my god this is so complicated is the
other one better
yeah this is way better i'm not doing
this we're doing the old one
i i i did the old one a long long time
ago um but this is i don't like i'm
already confused if they're asking me to
type all this stuff i don't understand
so rmd um most high school tutorials on
the web use a style of teaching akin to
language reference manuals
boring they show you the syntax of the
language a few language constructs
that tell you to create a few simple
functions at the interactive prompt
the hard stuff of how to write a
functioning useful program is left to
the end or omitted entirely
yeah all right now we're talking oh good
good good this looks this looks much
more approachable
let's start with main.hs
module main where import system dot
environment
okay that just sounds like boilerplate
crap main has
type i o i know types when i see them do
args equals get args uh
put sterling hello
i assume that's the concatenation
operator args
question mark question mark zero
all right well you gotta spell
environment correctly if you try to
import the environment you get nothing
all right cool we got a program
oh it's not okay index too large because
we're taking a zero with arc hello hello
hello
maine bob hello bob all right cool
um the type declaration
type declaration the io type is an
instance of the monad class
uh monad is a concept and no one in
haskell will ever give you a straight
answer to what a monad is
they'll tell you all this stuff about
how it's like grounded in some
you know seventh level math man but
maybe this is more to say a value is of
type moan added the class is to say
there's a certain type of extra
information
attached to this value most functions do
not need to worry about these pieces of
information
the extra information the i o actions is
to be performed using the carried along
value
well the basic value
when attached with information is void
represented as that
okay both i o string and i o parentheses
parentheses belong to the same i o monet
type
there's two ways to create an i o action
lifting an
ordinary value into the i o monad
combining two existing i o actions
all right this is what a do block is it
like puts the monad stuff together
precedence of haskell stuff okay cool
let's move on to parsing
oh we're gonna need a parser or cabal
install parsec
drive no it's 18 days old
you're asked to install executables but
there are no executables perhaps you
want to use lip
well let's just hope this works
hiding spaces yeah i mean because like
spaces is like like a
what's ghc main.hs dot slash main
okay gotta compile um
we'll define a symbol which is a parser
char all right that seems kind of nice
all right so symbol is just anything
there and then we're going to write a
read exper
let's type this one out read expert
string
to string read expert input
case parse symbol
lisp uh i don't know where i got the
word lisp from
input
of left error
no match plus plus show error
right val found value okay it's
something
can i like put my read expert what if i
put my read expert here
that do something
no no match list oh it's trying to like
match the word lisp
unexpected l or i guess i can only parse
these things so if i put like a bunch of
stars it's good
would you get an m
i gave you an m
hello found value oh
who knows why it's m oh yeah echo star
yeah that's not a star
you know when the first star you see may
not be a star yes you gotta you guys
gotta pay attention to the songs you
know
uh
[Laughter]
i'll say yeah never mind
um
yeah let's tie more people out let's
boot more people you know
people people think they can do whatever
they want on the internet we need
standards
i think this whole place needs standards
um this is why the moderation problem is
is such a problem
all across the internet a lot of people
have gotten away with terrible behavior
that they never behave that way in
public um the way that i
act on streams is really very similar uh
to how i act in in
in uh
you know life i'm not anonymous my name
is george hawks
um and this is a representation of who i
am you trying to use you know brand
to like you know like say like oh you
got a brand you gotta you gotta act a
certain way
but like some of you guys act anonymous
and you can make a website
here's here's an interesting website
what if you make a website it's like
troll trace from south park
which is everybody's internet comment
history
next to their real name um and
here's here's maybe how it works right
you're either cool with that and you can
continue to comment on the internet or
if you're not cool with that you're
banned for
forever commenting from the internet
again it'd be great
uh facebook and the real name policy you
know
you'd be so not cool with that good get
the out of my channel don't come in
here again
anyone who wouldn't be okay with that
don't talk in my channel
done
ah
[Music]
expert that get args
put spur sterling
breed expert expert
cool all right
we wanted to add white space we're going
to add support for white space and
that's why we had to hide spaces so we
can add a spaces type
now this is all using the parsec library
which i mean this is the kind of thing
where we could dive into exactly what it
is
maybe we have extra time we can
implement a parser
um because it would be fun
but yeah so here we want spaces
symbol
oh skip many one maybe
all right so now we can parse things
that have spaces i'll make this a little
bigger so you guys can all see
who's complaining about the moderation
policies oh let me see this
i'm mentally unfollowing you then
following you back
alright uh
is he always like this yes um
yes sub only mode
uh we touched briefly on the bind
operator in lesson two
we mentioned it was used behind the
scenes to combine the lines of a do
block
here we use it to combine our white
space and symbol parses
however bind has different semantics in
the parser and i o yeah this
can be based on whatever the uh
type is okay cool
so we're back to defining uh lispval
atom is a string
you don't have to do any text stuff um
i mean that was like that was my
complaint about that last tutorial
they're introducing
to me what seems like a political battle
going on in the haskell community about
whether string or text is the one true
thing
like get the noobs early no no string is
the one true string oh no it's slower
yeah watch me n squared concatenate my
strings together in python and not
care um number
integer string string
pool pool all right that seems pretty
reasonable
um this is an example of an algebraic
data type it sold a set of possible
values of type list val
atom list dotted list
cool all right so we want
a thing that parses par
string and i guess parser
list vowel so the output is a list bell
do char so if it's a string we're going
to get a char
here x mini
none of backslash
uh that end quote return
and that's for like uh association
alright cool all right par string
parse adam we can just copy and paste
this in
now we'll type it out it's quick
so this is a lisp atom and we can see
what the uh
i really like all that tabbing we'll see
if it makes me do it
letter symbol so i assume that's a
parsec's version of an
ore so you guys can look up parsec i've
used it before
it's a haskell parsing library
magnetic parser combination star
constraint is an industrial strength
pricing library a simple safe well
documented has extensive libraries good
error messages and is fast
it is it is defined as a monad
transformer that can be stacked on
arbitrary monads
it's also parametric in the input stream
type i don't really know what those
words mean
library for writing parsers and haskell
it's based on higher order parts or
combinators
so a complicated parser can be made out
of many small ones
and re-implemented in many other
languages that's nice
i mean a challenge here would be like
you know i'm kind of i'm kind of copying
here
um i'm just typing what's here but a
real challenge would be to like
translate this into a different
programming language
let atom equals first colon rest return
case atom of uh
cool true so i've seen this before this
is just
scheme syntax uh for getting true
and then um in haskell when you're doing
pattern matching like this
uh this just means match anything
so that's what that does there see if
that compiles
uh oh yeah list i think i made the same
typo last time too didn't i
somebody called me out for it in the
comments
um any advice on how to start with
reverse engineering so you're going to
get a timeout
this has nothing to do with what we're
doing right now um
do i think learning haskell is valuable
and why absolutely not like everything
on these streams it's a complete waste
of time
if you're here to learn something useful
go to college and get an mba and scam
people
um
yeah just no it's not live
big you duckus
parser list val oh god a lift em
i know these things do something with
monads but i don't really know what
number dot read
many one digit
this shows one more way of dealing with
monadic values
it's easiest to read this backwards
since both function application and
function composition associate to the
right
the parsec combinator many one haskell
also has
very good documentation and the stronger
types get the stronger you can make
documentation kind of automatic
well i mean that's sad but um
we'd like to construct a number list
spell from the resulting string but we
have a few type mismatches
first we use the built-in function read
to convert that string into a number
then we pass the result to number which
is this thing up here to get a lisp val
function composition operator creates a
function that does both together
oh okay unfortunately the result of many
digits is still a parser string
so our combined number reads still can't
operate on it
we need a way to tell it to operate on
the value inside the monad
lift m does exactly that so let's try a
little experiment
well oh we're going to have to
import control monet and we're going to
try a little experiment where we'll see
if we get a tight mismatch if i get rid
of that lift then
i mean i should
so yeah it's it's
inside this so this is the monad that
it's inside of and lift
m is applying this function see i never
could have
okay question am i learning right now
i'm not really sure right
i think they have exercises at the end
of these and we'll do the exercises to
make sure we really
you know check my understanding um
because like i can say this but i never
would have known
if i had gotten this error i would have
been like i lift am i i wouldn't have
guessed that right
um cool so there's some uh things we're
gonna have to think in a little bit
um this hasn't been thinking yet this
has just been typing
parser list val
so parse expression just seems to be a
combination
and we'll move this down here since it's
a combination of the previous three
parse atom
parse string or parse number we can get
any one of these and it's all an expert
um so i guess we want to yeah we want to
want to find read experts so instead of
calling this spaces symbol thing
we'll call parse expert and i guess lisp
is just like the name of the top token
or something
um yeah well so i don't need val here
because it's actually not used
okay so let's see if i just make it true
does that work yeah cool
um rewrite
parse number okay well let's double
check
let's take a look okay that works
rewrite parse number
with outlift m
using do notation and explicit
sequencing
with the oh wow i've never seen that
operator before
but let's think about how to do this so
how do i write a comment again with
haskell
comments weird well that doesn't work uh
something like that
there are just two dashes i can do
single line comments yeah okay cool
that's good
um using do notation
and explicit sequencing so what if i
just say something like
do uh
first many one
digit or i say like x and then i say
something like return
this uh
well so what do i want to do i want to
read x
and then i want to call number on that
i think i can actually just that does
the same thing
um yeah so how does that work
cool my god does the same thing um
i don't know how to do explicit
sequencing with this operator i guess
they want me to write another one but
yeah
uh
yeah that seems it seems right um so i
can also
just show like that's equivalent i can
do that as well
uh because i left a parenthesis there
cool cool but i think i think our first
check your understanding went pretty
well
uh i don't really care about this type
i don't really get um i don't know i
don't care about that one
we did half of it our strings aren't
quite
r5 rs compliant because they don't
support escaping of internal quotes
within the string
uh change parse string so that
that gives a literal quote character
instead of terminating the string
oh change parse number to support the
scheme standard for different bases
add a character and a float constructor
uh you guys in the comments decide which
one we want to do here i don't want to
do them all we'll do one
um
full numeric tower well that sounds like
a lot uh you guys can choose from two to
six
and then whichever one people like will
do
all right what are we saying six all
right all right i see a lot of votes for
float
let's do float uh add a float
constructor to lisp val
okay so i think we can say float float
where is haskell haskell float type
oh they're 12 doubles or something i
don't know we'll see first let's see if
that works okay
so we expect something like 3.4 to
compile
oh it already compiled well that's
somewhat concerning
what did it parse us
it would be helpful if we had a way to
print these i think there is a type
what if i you know
found val plus plus show val it's gonna
be like oh you can't show a list valve
um how do i make my custom type showable
haskell make type
showable
no instance from show this val it's like
a way to do this though
oh import debug.trace and then use trace
m
string thank you
um
do you have an associative problem any
friends there
no trace tray
show
bob
driving show okay all right let's try
that approach
sorry tracem
uh driving shell
like that oh hell yeah that works okay
found value number three
oh so i guess it just parsed that
um so that's a little annoying
because i don't know which is going to
what's going to take precedence
parse float do
many digits
why many digits
uh let
atom equals
no this isn't right
it's a way i can like get that whole
thing right
um
i should do i think i can sequence them
with this
and then the haskell function read float
might be useful
so i guess that's the same then as this
so we'll just copy and paste this and
change that to read
float and we'll call the float
constructor instead of the number
constructor
and then we'll add it here so we can
parse float as well
variable not in scopy hey probably
because i need to like import it or
something
numeric dot read float orders need to
import numeric
no module named numeric is important
import
numeric
couldn't match type float with
actual type double string
i don't know how i feel about that
why is it a string oh read float must do
some fancy
reads an unsigned
real frack
is that the wrong read float
no i'm starting to write read flow
yeah hugo
so we want something that's going to
take in a float taking a string
and return a float isn't that right
floatmer maybe he's not a haskell type
maybe doubles the right answer
read double oh this is from some bio
library though
well actually i should be able to type
read float into google and it'll tell me
stuff right
oh god what's a red s
reads an unsigned real fraction
um i don't know reed didn't have these
problems
a parser for type a and returns a set of
possible pairs
can you put a show there no of course
not there are like ways to
uh see something that's annoying about
haskell how do i debug
i think i can just use read as long as i
can infer that i'm parsing a float okay
let's try it
ground value float 4.0 great well that
wasn't exactly the float that i wanted
eh
i mean i guess it parsed this and then
well all right let's first do a little
test what if i do string x all right
that should
why did it get a four where'd it get
four
oh it like didn't it didn't concatenate
these
so reed might actually be correct but
i have a problem here with my
concatenation
um
so like let atom equals x colon colon
y or plus plus
um there's probably a better way to
write this
let atom equals and then we'll check to
make sure it's working as a string
we don't want that we want that
okay now it's saying 3.4 so now we can
return
float read adam let's go cool
do i need that i don't need that
beautiful
um
oh we don't want to ignore hs
cool
drops the intermediate values is there a
way not to
you can try with a tight hole to debug
your types
yeah i've seen that before thank you for
subscribing
my philip 3 um
cool all right we now have float support
uh next we're going to add a few more
parser actions
uh so we should be able to parse a list
parse list is a parser this vowel
parse list uh this is using the lift m
syntax again
but i think we're pretty comfortable
with that
uh sep by this must be parsec stuff
parse x first braces okay the parse
expert this is actually
down here in the hierarchy
uh the dotted parser list is slightly
more complex
parse dotted list is a parser list bound
do we already have
support for these things yes we do in
our algebraic data type oh that's
beautiful
i'm going to start getting some scheming
soon parse expert spaces
i don't know what end buy is maybe does
google support parsec
yeah n by parses zero more
okay that's fine yeah zero more and then
i get it
separated and ended bicep
uh char
spaces yeah so it really is only doing
it's only doing the parse expert these
are being thrown away
and that was my bug and that's why i had
to write that but i'm sure you can write
it much better
um keeps them and you can bind them in a
lambda
well that's that thing that i didn't
understand
see you saying i can do this
well let's uh let me comment it out and
see if we can write a better version of
parse float
always be improving yourself always be
improving a b
c improvement doesn't start with c
george says so many wrong things on the
stream
uh so we want to use this guy
oh let's list val again
uh my car is not the best guy let's
finish writing this one out the turn the
type is dotted list
head tail
it doesn't work
the function on the right hand needs to
accept an argument
so many one digits
that thingy well
no but see i don't think that's gonna
work because char there
is um i need the char i need the actual
dot as well
i need the dot you know what let's let's
let's uh let me post this to github
and then uh you guys can do we can do
some live pull requests on here
um you know what i'm gonna uh
should be able to not not that i'm gonna
hide my screen for a sec
while we do github
you guys can see me though while we do
github um
so what should we call the repository
haskell haskell scheme
uh haskell scheme
writing
myself a scheme
in way less than
48 hours should we go on all night boys
we got two things of tea
let's go let's go
all right so somebody can post a link to
that
uh and now we can bring the screen back
yeah buddy
uh yeah i've seen rebel autograph all
right
uh so now we can go over to my github
anonymously uh yeah haskell scheme
uh we should actually write a quick
readme just to give
credit where credit is due following
make sure this link works
cool tutorial
cool
all right we'll let you all talk again
uh and we'll see
uh said zero f congratulations you're a
moderator
you said smart things
and if the dumb things come back we'll
go back to the subscriber only
and one of these days i'm not i'm not
sure what i'm going to do yet
like we had a quiz and to be honest not
enough people passed the quiz
to do it only people who pass the quiz
can talk
uh but one day we are going to do
something about the general level of
dumbness in the chat
um i'm not i'm not a partner yet
uh i got to do like three more streams
this month and then we'll see if they
give it to me
uh if they give it to me i'll be more
active on twitch if they don't give it
to me
yeah remember that time i was a twitch
streamer
everyone's got to have a career doing
something man some other guy in the
things was like i don't like when this
guy is always chilling for subscribers
does she not
have money uh and the answer to that
is yes i'm broke so please subscribe and
the real answer to that
is you subscribing gives me validation
that i'm doing something good
it's like following but it costs money
and it's just you know it's like it's
like it's like praise man
you know and i appreciate praise uh
who doesn't appreciate christ but also
you always wonder you put something out
of the world and you're like is this
thing
do people like it or not
um
i know no i understand people on twitch
are all like this
uh it's not i know it's it's not my
channel but what i'm saying is
i want my channel to be a a is the word
respite
respite respite you know yeah
a respite from the siege of the
terribleness of the internet um
whenever i use words like i use words
that like come into my mind
and then like does this word means what
i think it does and then i google it
does this word mean what i think it does
yeah
that's what i meant to say um
cool we did that
uh we got to add single quoted syntactic
sugar
what is this note how we can sequence
together
and then yeah that's cool
the sequence returns a parser and then
combining that with a parse expert as a
parser list val exactly the type we need
for the do block
now let's add support for the single
quote
syntactic sugar
let's google this
uh when you single quote it oh it
doesn't evaluate it okay
i've seen this before
um and then oh what's the structure and
interpretation of computer programming
yeah you know would be really cool if we
do this
book um it's a free book too i believe
actually i think i have it in my ibooks
do i have it in my ibooks no i don't
i also got another book today
recommended by martin shkreli margin of
safety
um yeah this can we get the pdf of this
so this is a thing written in scheme i
just want to quickly look at it and see
if the scheme
looks uh similar to my scheme
oh no i do have it here structure
interpretation key program is cool
um yeah i went through this a bit when i
was playing with backspace
uh
yeah this looks like my scheme we should
try we should try some of the examples
from this book
in the scheme just so we know that what
we're doing is not like
you know some it's something real that
exists outside
of just being in this tutorial
and it's not all made up it's real
programming boys
real programming uh structure
interpretation computer programming is
like uh
one of the freshman books at mit um
i think it's pretty good remember if the
book's more than
let's say if the book came from earlier
than 2000 it's probably good i'd like to
survive this long
finally let's add
our definition to parse expert to
include the new parsers but
put the parse expert calls the things
which also calls
parks expert that's too much that's too
much
man it's too much it's too recursive
will this ever terminate you can't prove
it anymore
oh man this would be so terrible see
that's why i'd be so terrible to doing
like
something non-turn complete like
like i'd have to show that this
because it's recursive right parse list
calls parse expert which you can call
parse list
so you have to show that the total
number of unconsumed characters is
what what is this spam
oh the other thing that i wanted to talk
about from the previous stream
you guys i wasn't ripping on web
developers
it wasn't web developers who i was
ripping on when i was talking about crud
apps
you know you want to code front-end
stuff there's some incredible front-end
stuff i do not want to hate on front-end
people who i want to hate on
is the people who make themselves
subservient to business people
the people who see themselves as like
you know someone's like oh is fang all
crud apps
well think of who you you're you're
you're putting yourself underneath
right um that is
is who uh i'm complaining about when i
complain about the crud apps or like you
work for some government to make some
like stupid forms so somebody can
upload some identity card or something
like that's that's what i want to
complain about not uh
not not the use of a certain type of
language to create
you know web apps also okay i guess i
also want to complain about like the dog
walking apps and these kind of
no you know
like it's it's just it's just it's just
crud
okay parse there return
x all right so we should now be able to
parse a list i believe
misty oh no
unexpected space oh no i think my floats
broke it
my floats broke it we're gonna put the
float down there and it fixes it
but then i don't think my floats work
anymore
yeah i think um
maybe try parse float
yeah yeah remember that you gotta do try
yo sometimes you just gotta try now
we're talking
all right that's nice all right we can
make lists
let's let's bring up our structure
computer programs
um and like see if we can like do things
like that i don't think so because i
don't think we can do symbols yet
um whoops
sorry
i don't think plus is gonna work there
oh adam plus
wow fancy boys look we're parsing all
these thingies in the real book
i think we can even parse 2.7 and 10
thanks to you guys choosing floats
um
who's spamming mods can we take
care of the spammers
you know what you know what it's just it
gets lower quality it gets lower quality
we actually had someone who knew stuff
about haskell in here talking like
that's pleasant you know know something
or get the out
that's right wow
imagine that as a principle of society
know something or get the out
wow that'd be a nice society man
cool and we can check our dotted lists
too i don't exactly understand dotted
lists found
value dotted list yet and that's nice
okay
um which of the exercises do we want to
do
does he use try in other places oh yeah
try parslist yeah
oh try parsnip and par that should work
yeah that's nice cool
um
so which one do we want to do do we want
to do add support for the
back quote syntactic sugar
i kind of hate back quotes because that
quote is my
thing in scheme and every time i want to
back quote i have to press back code e
uh add support for vectors
a vector should have oh that looks too
hard
no never mind these all a card
you guys want to do i don't understand
let me see what vectors are
these might all be bad we know it um
vectors
are heterogeneous structures whose
elements are indexed by
integers now this is this is too much
it's too much
too much we're not doing any of these um
well let's see how bad let's see what
that quote is
quasi quote qq template
are you looking for constructing huh
i don't really get it
wow it's amazing we're seeing we're
seeing uh spam by
subscribers get out
you know to think you spent your
hard-earned money and now you can't even
post here anymore because
there's got to be i mean just because
you have money
doesn't mean you're allowed to to write
dumb
um yeah i don't know in fact
i don't know what vector is i didn't say
no everything i said no things
um and be honest when you don't know
things and go learn things
don't ask dumb questions like where do
you find
motivation and did i tell you my stupid
story about that yet
once upon a time i was idling on a
twitch channel
and i asked the guy where he found
motivation and he gave me a really
deep answer
yeah and now we're never going to repeat
that answer so i hope you guys heard it
hacky hacks thank you for subscribing
i don't understand what these things do
we're moving on we're moving on we're
moving on
we want this scheme to actually run
stuff soon so we're going to start doing
some evaluation
um currently we've just been printing
out whether we recognize
wow i don't know if we need this
i wrote my own show and i like my show
actually somebody on the stream told me
driving show and i appreciate deriving
show man you're a good person
um
onwards list instant read expert
found show value i already did that yeah
cool so we can just have parser here
unexpected single quote didn't i write
single quote oh did i not include parse
quoted
i had to like include this somewhere
didn't i
right there cool
yeah adam quote number one number three
list that
i don't know i kind of like that better
what did i add
beginnings of an evaluator primitives
okay cool so
let's go put this in a different can i
put in a different file
i know how to do that so we won't do
that just put it here
we'll write a couple comments data types
here we'll put parser
and here we'll put
eval eval takes in a lisp vowel
and it returns a lisp val eval
val at what does the at do
the notion val at string
matches any lisp vowel that's a string
and then
binds val to the whole list val and
notches the contents of the string okay
that's cute
so this is a normal like uh what are
these things called
this is like a type matching
comprehension there's a real name for
them
but if it's a string it matches that one
if it's a number
it matches this one it's a bool it
matches this one
and if it's a c but now this one's going
to be different we're not going to use
the add syntax
if we have a quote val then we just
return
val which i don't exactly understand
let's
the quote means like make it exactly
that and don't evaluate it
quote yeah return through without
evaluating it
cool i don't like you but
man i do enjoy your content get banned
wow you know didn't your mother ever
tell you if you don't have anything nice
to say
don't say it
now there's a there's an exception to
that which is
if you have something nice to say but
you don't it's not nice but it's true
true supersedes nice but your opinion of
whether you like me or not
that's not like true or false that's
just that's just and that's why
you're banned
i know but like it's stupid man it's
stupid
you know do we want just think think
is the channel better or worse for never
having that guy post again
and i think the answer is better
when we change our main function to read
an expression
get args uh oh wow this is a lot of
oh no get args
print eval read exper head
what okay so that's already head there i
don't even need to change this that much
i can just do eval here can i
uh like x equals eval expert
oh no i want to do read exper read
expert expert and then we can just put
out the thing that we evaluated
cool could not match type
io string with type list val
oh yeah um so let's do
show there and then we want
read expert to return a lisp vowel
oh that's cute so now the string is
actually an error in the language
yeah that's nice all right
i gotta spell lispval correct and can't
keep writing list vowel
could not match statement of type i o
with type
list val but read expert should take in
a string which exports a string type
it's because i have a dewblock or
something
okay maybe instead of here what if i
just say eval
uh read expert expert and we don't put x
there
oh no we're gonna need a show we need a
show that's the problem
i had a show there though um
read expert expert yeah that's good cool
uh so now it's going through if you
notice my quote here went away
because of this uh pattern match here in
my email
cool that's nice
um oh yeah now things are getting
exciting
watch this boys watch this if we try to
like add two plus two in our scheme
yeah non-exhaustive patterns and
function eval because we're going to
have to implement
a plus and now it's time to implement a
plus
so if we have a list with an atom func
and then args
so what this is doing is this takes the
first
item from the list this is the rest of
the list
we're going to apply is apply a haskell
built-in i think it is
yeah i don't know
uh
i don't really get it but whatever
apply funk map
eval args
well oh no i gotta write apply
uh so actually you know what let's just
try to write apply without reading ahead
so we want to apply this is an
atom a list val
and it's going to return a list val
if the atom is atom plus
um no this is actually a list here
is that this the syntax for lists
um equals
so like x and we can say number
some x
uh not in scope
well let's just try that for now
not in scope adam uh yeah and
wait what why is adam not in scope i
don't get it
list adam plus
non-exhaustive patterns in function eval
okay
so that matches that pattern oh
it's not an atom it's a funk is
actually being taken here so it's
actually a string
so we don't actually need the word atom
here we can say string here
so like that
couldn't match type integer with actual
type list value yeah we're gonna have to
unpack them
yeah so the problem with those x's is
their list vowels
so i mean i could i could like i could
write a little helper function called
like on number
which is stupid but goes something like
this
uh and it is number right now it's
integer
um
a number number x equals
x and i think if i say like some map on
number x
that works construction number should we
have one argument yes
it's gotta be putting parentheses
okay cool so that did return four i do
think there's a nicer way to write that
but you know i think we're pretty good
on the check our understanding okay
so we got the type for apply correct
um apply
funk args maybe
bull for false
oh fancy
maybe cool force what is a haskell maybe
it's like a type
here's the function maybe if the
function isn't found
we return a bull false but otherwise
this is a look up
okay
i don't know where it looks that up
maybe is applied to too few arguments
oh this isn't a comment wow
wow that was that was look up
funk primitives oh i thought this was
like a comment
i can't see all right um so now we have
primitives which is this data type
that's kind of like a map data type from
string
uh it returns something that takes in a
list and returns a single value
it's pretty nice and then we can write
out some of these primitives
uh here we have plus
i guess that's a numeric bin op
of type plus
we can copy and paste that not much will
be gained from typing that
all right
um i think numeric bin op is a function
that we're going to have to write
oh we got to put an equals there oh i
got to tap that over one
cool uh variable not in scope
okay so numeric been uh look but it
tells us the type how beautiful
your integer integer
okay
all the integers
oh okay that's actually a function here
so we'll just say like f
args actually
we know what the r's we want to match
are number
x comma number y
and then we'll return f x y
uh
uh oh we have to return a number
numerical
is that right
this character oh tab character oh god
and
haskell hates tabs as much as i do
set et
cool
now let's check how closely i wrote that
to what they wrote
seems pretty good um
oh well okay that's kind of nicer well
they actually wrote an unpack
numb that's kind of that function i
wrote before that i threw away remember
this vowel integer
[Music]
we'll just do that for now um so they
called it
op and they're using fold l the problem
with my implementation here is it only
supports two
arguments uh my other one didn't because
i did
some but uh fold l1
op map unpack num on params
cool now two plus two
that still works we can also add a three
in there then we get seven oh that's
nice sexy bros
all right um
we implement a form of weak typing i
don't like this week typing
no weak typing
you'll throw a type error at the haskell
level about incomplete patterns
um so let's see if this works
i'm gonna nest and see if we get a
five oh yeah five
yeah let's see if this works
change unpack num so that always returns
zero well that's what i want to do
anyway
that's right everything else be a number
or be
zero
add the symbol handling functions
add primitives all right which one
should we do
what's your keyboard wow
do you listen bro you get a timeout
maybe you just you know don't listen
you guys want three
one
uh
yo what's the mouse boss california all
right all right
uh why do you think we're talking about
the singularity
i think zero for everything else is
related to nil
punting i don't know what mill punting
is i just didn't want to write that
other code
because i think it's ugly and i think
that you know get your types right um
yeah i don't know about this okay uh
what do we want to write
we like one or we like three
let's let's write let's write one let's
do one one looks pretty easy
hey guys you all want three all right
can someone explain to me what three
is add symbol handling functions
returns true if
obj is a symbol
are they like atoms
symbol is what we've been calling an
atom
okay okay we can give this a try
let's see what we got symbol
question mark foo
false but foo is supposed to be a symbol
what is just foo it's an atom foo but i
don't understand
oh
so like
but that's an atom plus
return
whoa wait this is a lot of functions you
guys want me to write
i like eq that one seems like something
we can implement i like eq
that should return true
how does it know to return false
where is that false oh that's just in
the maybe okay cool
um so we'll add some primitive function
uh eq
we can call it
um compare
it's a bin op i thought a bin op only
took in two things
i don't know compare been up
uh we don't actually need to write the
type for this one
let's say that it's only if we have atom
x
atom y in the list
uh otherwise it returns
false equals
bool x equals equals y
variable not in scope oh
let me just compare it up oh i don't
have an
op i don't know
i mean that works right non-exhaustive
pattern and function eval
we'll get it though this should be a
funk
lookup funk primitive eval which
this should be an atom i believe we
can't eval an atom but that's an atom
fine
um
be bites back thank you for gifting subs
to people
i appreciate you you are a good person
go imagine mr beast came in here and
gifted
everybody a sub
uh you know
uh bee bites back if you have a question
i will take your questions seriously
you get a real answer won't even try to
troll
what do you think of pvm well i don't
know what pvm is
oh virtual machine
um
is a tool for parallel networking of
computers
it is designed to allow a network of
heterogeneous unix computers
to use the single distributed parallel
processor
so my immediate
thought about this is
what you the main problem you have here
um so even even within a dual xeon
system
it's a pneuma architecture it has
non-uniform memory access right
so the problem with
with doing this is you have different
bandwidth links to different parts of
your memory see i want
multiple processors to act on the same
bit of data the question is where do i
store the data
well so i have a few options i can store
the data on one machine probably local
to let's say one of the processors
but then every time the other machine
wants to access that data
it has to go across the network and the
network is much slower than the bus
that links the processor to the memory
um
so you can another way to deal with this
is to have two copies of the data
in the memory of both machines uh but
then you need some way to synchronize
them you're gonna need some kind of like
uh caching mechanism uh what do they say
there's two hard problems in computer
science and one of them is cash
invalidation
so that's my like analysis
right away of something like this like
it can't exactly be
automated um pvm consists of a
runtime environment library for message
passing task and resource management
so yeah i mean as a anything that's a
library libraries are always nice
um but i think there's there's like
mpi yeah and i've seen or like m-p-i-c-h
you know build your beowulf cluster
uh but yeah so i don't know what the
advantages would be over
uh something more modern that kind of
does this but there's no way to do this
for free
it's always going to be somewhat tricky
to uh
use um
you mean a different pvm well okay now
let's look at this pvm
predictive vision in a nutshell
but see when i give a real analysis on
something without troll look it's like
real
so let's um starcodex has to say
there an archive post or something
unsupervised learning from continuous
video um so my immediate thought is okay
it's gbt3 for video
and of course gpt3 for video works
really well now actually build it
let's see what actual results they got
so one of the problems in general with
video prediction
and i'm not sure they deal with it in
any kind of good way
is what's your output space
uh so if you're if your output space is
images what's your loss function on
images
something like msc or mae probably
doesn't capture what you want
you can use sophisticated things that
try to capture structure like ssim
or you can use gan style loss functions
which are unstable
um so that's my first thought to this
uh and then another great way to
immediately evaluate any machine
learning paper
is look for the actual benchmark that
they
are um that they are state of the art on
so they're going for tracker benchmarks
okay compared it with these things
i'm going to archive for that i'm sure
github is still up
there's brain corps
how did they get outputs from this thing
so what's their actual loss function
primary signal predictive so
i don't know why you need all of this
complexity
um what's their
real loss function
i don't know um so
i i could spend if i really wanted to
dive into this paper it would take an
entire stream
um all video prediction things
you you have to ask a few questions uh
one is
is the is the prediction that they're
doing
context specific or context free um
at comma when we build models which
effectively compress
driving video we ignore things like the
trees
um and we do this in an unsupervised way
because the trees are irrelevant
the exact shape of the trees are
irrelevant to how to drive the car
uh so if you're building things that
just predict video
humans don't really do this humans
always have our specific context in mind
um so i'm not sure like if
they do that here uh
and then the other question is are you
reasoning are you trying to predict an
image space
or are you trying to predict in some
vision feature space
i think that predicting an image space
is the wrong idea
uh because i don't think they're doing
image space
i think it's something else
uh but if you ask the question
can you build gpt3 for video it's a
classic link you think oh gbt3 you know
what if i just took all the youtube
videos and put them into one huge auto
encoder
um well so unfortunately you don't get
the beauty of gpt 3's loss function
uh gpt3 is just this loss function
um it's categorical cross-entropy
category cross entropy is is a
beautifully simple loss function
that can be used because there are not
that many tokens in your language space
even if you have like
uh you know 8 000 right that's that's
only 8 000 dimensions
of output versus for video
well it's not even it's it's
not even the number of pixels because
what you're not
capturing there is joint representations
even if you had an output for each pixel
which is way more than 8 000 dimensions
what about in pac-man where a ghost
could go to the left or a ghost could go
to the right
right that's the you have to capture
that joint distribution
not blur the ghost both ways
um
[Music]
you don't care about gpg3 why not
well it's not rude to say you don't care
about gbt3
when you took the time to explain it it
is
don't let the hype interfere with what
it actually is whether it's over hyped
or under hyped or whatever it doesn't
matter
why do you think it's not really solving
anything i kind of think just scaling
those things up and you're going to
solve the turing tests
and it's going to be a late it's going
to be a sad truth about humanity
that most people i mean here's a
question
how many people are already worse
writers and dumber than gpt-3
and then what gp3 gpt is going to get
most of humanity
so
uh
yeah i mean i don't know gbg3 is
probably higher quality
than some of the commenters um in here
okay non-exhaustive
pattern match in function eval
why is that why is this not a list with
arcs
it is a list with arcs and the first one
is an atom i don't get it
i don't get why this isn't exactly that
uh
oh because i'm mapping eval arbs okay i
think
i'm not sure why i didn't have that it's
probably some good reason okay that's
true and that's false okay cool
we wrote eq
i think parsing floats was broken by the
eval stuff
oh well i got an eval
float
uh yeah let's see can we add two floats
zero that's right that's right zero
um oh no
unpack num
yeah well you can't add floats add only
works on integers
yeah yeah you can add three and three
but don't add 3.4
and point four
um i don't know i mean gpe three starts
to show where the problem with the
target test as a formulation is
uh ben gortz will propose the coffee
test and i prefer the coffee test
we don't need error checking do we this
seems like a lot of stuff to write
for just errors
um i prefer the coffee test it's can you
build a robot that can go in the average
american's house and make a cup of
coffee
12-hour type mismatch
yeah i think errors are boring let's go
on to evaluation part two
additional primitives
these seem pretty useful
a wozniak proposed the coffee test oh
even better
uh let's let's just for correct citation
uh coffee tests ai
damn it is wozniak that's crazy
oh gorgeous yeah you know what that
doesn't even
get go you go get a degree in some
post-modern
um damn cool
uh i love you know reading about like
apple history growing up in wozniak
it's cool
i need error checking no we don't need
error checking that's boring
we'll add some error checking if errors
become a real problem
for now
let's add these guys for more evaluation
um
these both take exactly two arguments
yeah see but we don't have errors so we
can write this simpler
unpacker op
x comma y yeah
equals do left unpacker
oh we don't even need this we can just
saw it so much simpler when you don't
have errors
that's that numbers turn
cool left
turbo bin up unpack
stir and then
bubble bin app unpack pool
i'm gonna have to write these as types
here
we believe in strong typing
unpack stir
string s
return ass
um cool
couldn't match m7 list valve with list
val
i want to do wrong
all right all right we're we're over
talking about gbt we're we're talking
about that we're we're working on
something here boys
um
bin up oh it must not like that these
types don't match
um
no it's the return types that are wrong
let me just write the type signature for
bull bin up
uh so we take in this thing called an
unpacker uh
which is a list val
and returns i guess type a
a a bool
list val
it seems like errors went away since i
wrote that
maybe i had to write the a for the
polymorphism
this is the right case wrong and you
should have unpack y
oh yeah absolutely good catch
uh that doesn't explain what this
problem was
this just doesn't like these things
or my bull bull bin up is broken
two left
and packer x on packer y
let's type m1 bull
uh so this is a
unpack pool which goes from a lisp
val to a bool and this goes from a lisp
val to a string
let's add some more type so we can get
some better errors
couldn't match type char with char
huh
why do i need to return here i don't
because i'm not doing stupid throws
errors i can just do that
yeah now we're talking
couldn't match expected type list val
i don't think we need all this complex
stuff because we didn't do errors
can i just say uh bull
x up why
oh no we do need to pass it through
unpacker
yeah oh look our shit's so simple
because we didn't write anything
stupid oh well too bad three's not equal
to three i mean it'd be nice if three
was equal to three
but oh true also doesn't equal true so
you know we got to fix these things
equals equals actually isn't uh oh it's
not equals equals
yeah that's true but true oh it equals g
oh true equals false oh it's not good
um
equals three true true equals four false
oh yeah now we're talking
but i don't know why true equals false
that's not good
oh how we doing on look at some viewers
well
you know you guys like when i rant about
stuff i think more than actually
coding
free the pleb so we can spam that's not
that's not
appealing
i'll free the plebs if somebody figures
out why true equals false
i guess there's not a bull bull been on
for that
it's a number been up oh and they're
both getting set because they're being
parsed as numbers
oh i don't know
let's be a little more fair to the
numbers
and say because if i actually if i do
that i think that's going to return an
error
yeah non-exhausting pattern matches just
because i was nice with that
but if i say unpack num bool
let's say bool true and i return
one and then false i return zero
true no longer is equals false and since
i did figure it out
i will free the plebs and we'll see
if the plebs have anything to say or
they're going to talk
only be fade thank you for subscribing
what is your profession
a garbage man pizza delivery man yeah
pizza delivery
false equals false that's good
um let's let's go over to our
uh book here and see if our
things work um too bad let's figure out
where our floats don't add
let's figure out how to make our floats
at
non-exhaustive pattern match and unpack
numb oh
well instead of
integer here
i mean can i do that
hmm can't do that
yeah see that's a problem
we can't add our floats
cool that stuff works
let's see if this big long expression
actually gives us 57
naming the environment a critical aspect
of programming languages
the means it provides to use names to
refer to computational objects
in the scheme dialect public scheme
dialect of lisp we name things with
define
oh we're gonna have to make it define
cool false great
uh i don't like the way they did errors
in here they're very complicated
carl oh you're building a rebel oh rebel
would be nice
that sounds pleasant
let's add a raffle
um
flush string
read prompt those seems
like
it's a lot of functions
putster prompt
h flush standard out
and then we'll call getline um
errors are stupid
string io string eval string
equals return it's just
this um show
eval read expert extra
uh and we're gonna have this take in
extra
so then i should just be able to say
here put sterling
eval string extra doesn't work
actual type i o string
well because we returned it so it's in
the monad
this should keep it in the monad i think
yeah i know how to mow man all right
um and a function that evaluates the
string oh
look yeah oh we can use this oh that's
what that thing does
oh yeah haskell level 9000
yeah all right
so we want to put it in our loop
wow
eval and print that seems like a nice
thing
all right that noise is getting annoying
eval and prince takes in a string
and returns an io monad
all on its own so we can just
eval and print expert
um yeah cause that's not right
uh equals eval string
exper poster
57 cool now it's time to tie it all
together we want to read input perform a
function and print the output all in an
infinite loop
the built-in function interact almost
does what we want
so we need to roll our own loop
until pred prompt action
do results prompts
if tread
results
then return from the moan ad else
action result and then
call it again action
and then we'll just change our main
uh to do until
equals equals quit c don't you love the
currying of functions
uh we love carrying read prompts
let's bring that down here
put that in this section
[Music]
called rebel
it looks stupid when it's not
capitalized
compile error because i did oh uh
until quit we want to
read prompt list that's a stupid prompt
eval and print which is the function we
run
all right we have our lisp oh we have a
lisp
no match
oh number four look at our lisp
oh yeah oh if only we had those
oh that'd be nice what do i do rl rap
yeah rl rap boys
we'll do a run.sh
cool
who's saying wow
what are people arguing about yeah this
chat needs some moderation i agree
uh or maybe you should just get off the
internet zzyx
get the hell out of my channel uh you
know and people always are dming me
who's being racist do you want to get
thrown out too
um people are always dming me yo dude
can you unban me
no
please go and sub only
yeah yeah it's too bad it's too bad why
we can't have nice things
uh you know
it's too bad
welcome subscribers
no they can spend all their channel
points if they want to spend their
channel points and they want to say
their one thing
they can say their one thing and spend
their channel points
yeah look it's beautiful my list is my
scheme is
beautiful it's only 172 lines
oh okay they made oh adding variables
and assignment oh this sounds like the
kind of thing we need
in order to get through our book because
we have naming in the environment
oh this is all going to be hard though
wow how many sections does this book
have
we're making some progress
all right you know what we're disabling
channel points
help channel points guide
yeah i'm sold i'm sold you guys are
subscribers you're good people what are
channel points people do
how do i disable this
moderation
disable channel points channel points
here we go
how to earn channel points some
managing channel point rewards
get a dashboard and proceeding to
channel points under the community
section
oh um manage rewards and challenges
uh oh highlight my message oh yeah
that's the one that can go
uh send a message in sub-only mode no
that's okay but you can't send messages
in sub-only mode
damn this is pretty nice well you know
what
i have a better idea you can but it's
gonna cost you
seven million channel points
do you have 7 million channel points oh
that's what i thought you can't send a
message in sub only mode
please stop so you could spam you would
really suck if you subbed and then got
banned
that's why you don't spam
what an easy fix what an easy fix linux
with
five underscores i agree
okay we're gonna need an io and m
oh this looks hard oh this looks hard
oh it's got to take in an environment
now
oh this looks complicated
um
no this is gonna this is gonna be fun
this is gonna be fun
we're having fun here right we having
fun
let's let's drink some we're only
halfway through the tea
let's let's drink more tea let's take it
let's take a
two minute break and then we're gonna
write variables
and then we're gonna write some real
programs in our scheme
it's cool like how simple this is gonna
be when we're done we might have to
write errors but i don't like the way
they did it they added errors to
everything uh which might kind of just
be a limitation a haskell
but our scheme is doing so much nice
stuff already
richard l thank you for subscribing
oh we got it we gotta your twitch mods
are getting ridiculous
apparently any dissenting comment is
ground for time out and warrants the
leading of said comments
by the way the comment was
i don't know i don't know we're big on
censorship in this channel
you know what i mean this is a small
community we love censorship
kind of push to get up we just did
um no i mean
in real life you can give people so much
more of a benefit of a doubt than you
can give them on the internet
i think this is one of the problems with
internet communities period
and it kind of sucks that
like the real the moderation of internet
communities has been given over to these
companies who have no taste at all
um let's see what the pms say
okay thanks uh
no but i've been thinking about this
maybe this what we're gonna do on our on
our break
i've been thinking about this i've been
thinking about moderation
and how to build it's an age-old
problem it's politics
how do you build a good community and
the the politics that are in vogue in
silicon valley are kind of tasteless
uh so so far what we've done and there
happens to be a button for it is
subscriber only and
it's true that the person who subscribes
um at least has a credit card tied to
their accounts they're a real person so
they're less likely to say stupid things
i don't know how to do sub emotes
uh they want the revenues they allow all
people to twitch
yeah yeah and there's no i mean there's
no taste right
they value their value profit over taste
i mean there are some smaller internet
communities but i feel like they're kind
of dying out
um so two hypotheses
uh one hypothesis
i think i think actually i think i know
the the reason for this
um the average iq of the internet has
fallen
precipitously precipitously over the
last 30 years
69 operator chase quixote thank you for
subscribing
more people the bar is lowered yeah
you can create pockets yeah um
and we've got to be more deliberate
about how to do it
so if we go back to the quiz
only like six people did well enough on
the quiz
and this might be a
are there any communities we need to
pass a quiz to get in does anybody
like know about any online communities
one of the problems with personality
tests
is iq tests
you can't um a personality test
someone without the personality can game
it
uh if you actually have like let's say
you want like high conscientiousness
people right
if you if you want um or or agreeable
people
uh people know how to fake those things
you can't fake intelligence
i mean no but this isn't supposed to be
mensa
mensah is deliberately a
a intelligence based community
that's not what i'm going for here what
i'm going for
is a who's going to make intelligent
comments on a different
topic
what was the window to take the tests
one random stream we offered a test
oh the dms all the dms are there the dms
are all there
nope not clicking on any of you oh i
could i could click here
i could click ah but i'm not going to oh
but yeah i'm not going to
um yeah the turning paper annotated
tarring is nice to read
it's kind of hard to test people and
give them a fair chance
yeah i know they're so close their names
on the screen
change your username then you can get
some words on the screen
i mean no so i think you want a mix of
both i think you want a mix of
i think that in communities you want a
mix of um
so i think there's two things that are
acceptable to discriminate on
you can discriminate based on skill and
you can discriminate based on
paying money um if you think about how
like job interviews discriminate based
on skill college allegedly does
but it's you know actually based on
usually
uh racism or nepotism um
but you know theoretically it should
just discriminate based on skill if you
think about a bar with a cover charge
uh bar the cover charge is
discriminating based on
money so i think you do want both
we want both smart people and uh people
who are willing to contribute resources
it's not a question of their actual
wealth it's a question of whether
they're
willing to to contribute uh they're like
look you know i understand
that i might not be as good as the other
people here but i'm willing to
contribute
you know this right um this is the
classic
uh don't buy a girl drinking a bar
because what you're basically saying is
hi i understand my value is lower than
yours
but how about me and this appletini does
that level the scales a little bit
uh not saying don't ever buy a girl a
drink but don't open with that right
i didn't even count all the questions on
the test did i do something wrong i
might have done something wrong
uh but i don't think i was i was
i'd like the chat to stay on topic
what we did today was extremely
approachable
everybody could follow along with this
no i'm not gay and why would you ask
that say dumb like that again
and you're out of here
you know i don't care if you're a
subscriber you're banned
yeah today i mean i did it it is new
blessings i tried to make something that
was
followable today thank you for following
along
um
a question like what programming
language did you learn first i don't
like that's not a good question um and
it's not a good question because it's a
question that's
like it's totally meaningless i think i
said a few times how
i try not to talk about myself on these
streams because
my idiosyncratic life path doesn't have
anything to do with
skill it doesn't have anything to do
with anything that's real it's the same
thing with keyboards and terminals
and
um so what are examples of good
questions a good questions are questions
that lead to the discovery of truth
um like when we looked at that when we
looked at that paper earlier the
the the video predictive one yeah what
are your
well yeah what are your thoughts on
i mean honestly even what are your
thoughts on can be higher tier
than uh what programming language did
you learn first
um what is truth so truth is something
that if two people uh were to sit on
their own
uh and research something they would
come to the same conclusion
well let's say n people it doesn't have
to be two right it's something that is
objectively
discoverable through the universe
uh no i mean let's ask the internet
that's that's kind of my definition but
uh so another definition that i have for
truth
is anything that has predictive power
no truth isn't subjective opinions are
subjective
uh you pointed out that cs education is
bad i haven't done that into tetris
i think it's a similar sort of idea and
it might be a good test it might be a
good it might be a good course
yeah truth's not subjective this is
people who want to sell you hogwash you
know if you want to sell snake oil
instead of medicine
start out by telling people truth is
subjective
truth conforms to reality but maybe and
then you can maybe put a kind of value
hierarchy on truth and
the truths that allow you to predict
um the future are valuable
this is you say this is straight from
oh substantive revision
see i'm concerned about that revision
but we're all here we're all here
discovering we're all here together
science allows you to predict the future
so science allows you to compress the
past and if you can compress the past
you can predict the future
the book is writing a scheme in 48 hours
uh the
[Music]
on my github
it's here um
i don't know i'm
yeah please follow me on instagram
we're all on a journey of discovery here
together about where we want to end up
taking this channel
i saw something
one of the comments in the last video
was like
george is becoming more of a cult leader
every day
my only thought on that is well what if
we live in a world that no longer
believes in truth
but there's a cult that does believe in
truth
you know who's the cult
usually usually cults are are uh
demarcated by people believing dumb
like comet hail bop is going to beam us
all up to the starship enterprise
um you know and now people believe dumb
like uh well you know uh
biological sex is a social construct or
something like that right
i mean yeah the cult's called science
right
well this is what the university was
supposed to be i i
i think uh no i know what happened to
the anabaptists and jan von leiden and
man it didn't end well for them
you know
well i mean it doesn't matter whether
something calls itself science
ask whether it gives you power what does
it give you power over nature
we seek to find the power over nature
uh yeah listen to dan carlin's thing
about the at the end of that this is
good
um
when you're bringing up current day
stuff biological sex is not a social
construct right
everyone that's that's not even that's a
strong man it's it's not even
nobody actually says that but um i think
it's kind of along those lines
there's a lot of really shoddy thought
being done
um do we need like an faq
like george do you still do bounty hunts
faq i don't know
what am i doing here boys what is this
why do i have this twitch channel
what do i have nothing better to do with
my life it's a way to think
right if you want to build
why seek power over nature well if you
want to live forever i sure hope you can
get some nice power over nature right
yes to talk to myself right uh the
twitch bot can have faq
yeah well it's not an existential crisis
like
um
no thoughts on get out of here
living the examined life that's that's
that's a nice i've heard that like
examine life what's that from
no this is it's like socrates said this
why do i get all this modern crap
oh buy my self-help book on amazon
i have a phd
i developed thanks for the bits
yeah i'll have it in the title and
people will ask what i'm doing
but see the problem is the internet
boosts the loudest voices it's the one
who asks
i'm sure this is true that internet
commenters make up
a small fraction of the people in
society i certainly know twitter does
yet they are taken to reflect a new sort
of democratic consensus which is
meaningless the people who are
commenting on your youtube videos and
they're good to respond to and they're
good to kind of riff off of but to
believe that you're surveying the
general population with internet
comments it's just totally wrong
um actually i was gonna i was thinking
about
uh vitalik uh
one of the things i'm interested in
recently is homomorphic encryption
um
do you actually have any implementations
of this stuff
oh there's implementations this seems
kind of fun to play with
the problem with society is dumb people
are full of confidence while the smart
ones are full of doubts
i don't know maybe maybe that's a
problem
we're in the post enlightenment
yeah man but uh you know you don't build
uh you don't build
uh instruments of war with post
enlightenment ideals
you build them with enlightenment ideals
so
humans have far surpassed their capacity
for tech
when i hear an argument like that i
think back to like we have exceeded the
carrying capacity of the earth 10 times
over
no we haven't
i don't think i i don't think that the
prob
people attribute this this problem to
like cancel
culture and i don't think that's true
um i think that's just the the boogeyman
of the moment
you know there's always a boogeyman at
the moment right remember when the
terrorists were the boogeyman at the
moment
it's just it's it's the same
um thing playing out you can say like oh
well the reason that we all got
dumber is the terrorists i don't think
that i think that's just as true as the
cancel culture thing
um
make a list of banned comments and
normal comments well here's an
interesting question
yeah i mean what if we started
i mean i wonder if we could build
something so there's this thing called
uh
what is it it's like uh sentiment
analysis
so this is emotion but what if you use
technique similar to sentiment analysis
to extract like
i think we could at least ban off topic
comments well
what i'm more thinking about like of
course they'll always be bad comments
and you can ignore them and
if you're trying to do things on an
object level yes you can do this
but if you're trying to think about how
to build how can we build a higher
quality stream
uh now i mean part of this also is is
how much effort am i willing to put in
before i do the streams
how much effort do you want me to put in
before i do the streams one of the
compliments i'll get on this stream
is that i haven't pre-rehearsed any of
this material i'm doing it live in front
of you
um thank you anonymous gifter
anonymous see that's i can respect
anonymous you know
um blockchain the comment section proof
of stake right
these are these are ideas
a lot of the thinking in the crypto
world um
i've been reading uh i'm reading
vitalik's blog recently and
like um i've come around to proof of
stake i used to be anti-proof of steak
quadratic voting
uh i mean i've always been pro quadratic
voting i just thought it was too hard to
implement in practice
but like they're doing it um this is
like git coin
thing uh
they have like grants much into it too
much but
this stuff's really cool
bitcoin grants
yeah it's not that much money
um
quadratic funding i haven't spent a lot
of time thinking about this
and kind of how to attack it
can you machine learn what to ban by my
history of banned comments yeah
all right so that's i mean this is
something i say a common like all of you
here
uh you learn to you know what would i do
right run run your model of me in a
situation and then think about
uh you know if you don't know what to do
run your model of me right so i wonder
if you could do the same thing with the
comments here
um and it's not to say that like like
i'm not i'm not implying there that
my way of doing things is right
just as who i choose to ban it's not
right in any objective sense
but you know it's it's uh
well i'm not going to be upset
i want george larger and his computer
smaller we can do that we can do that
hacky hacks but that requires planning
oh if i announced the topics before
yeah um okay
so we'll announce i mean this is what's
nice to do
in in a few parts i think this is
today's stream
and what we'll do uh
it'll be either tomorrow or
tuesday around like 11 00 a.m
uh eastern standard time we'll come back
online
and we'll continue scheming in haskell
uh so if everybody could review
please review the book
please review structure and
interpretation of computer programming
and we're going to try to
implement some of the stuff from that
book in our custom dialectic scheme
no the bots they're not good enough yet
they're not good enough yet i do
have faith in the next decade
that we're going to be able to build
part of the problem part of the
moderation problem in general part of
the spam problem
is if it takes
less effort for the spammer to send the
message
then it takes even for you to just
delete it
spammers are totally winning in the
world
um but if we can have ai moderators
like
only will this delete trolls
this will also make trolling a less
productive activity it'll be less
economically incentived
uh incentivized because those trolls or
those spammer or those
salesmen or whatever they are they're
just hitting up against a machine
that they're no longer hitting up
against a person
um will there be a test i will try to
write a test
uh i will write a test so so yeah i'll
write
all right i'll write a little haskell
test uh
it'll be on stuff covered in this stream
so if you paid good attention in this
stream
you'll be able to do well on the test
i see you guys really like when i make
tests apparently i graded the last test
wrong though so i'll do
we'll do better we'll do better um yeah
please study for the test
and then i don't know how do you guys
feel about my other idea if we want to
actually do lessons for noobs
um maybe we'll do uh you know what we'll
do an auction
we'll do an auction uh if i ex this is i
don't know how much effort this is to
put together
uh but if someone wants to spend an hour
on stream uh learning a topic
uh who's ever willing to to bid the most
we'll say we'll say you put in a bid and
you put in
the topic that you want and the top one
might not get
chosen
quadratic funding yeah i'll have to
learn more about quadratic funding
please only vips
i hope vips can speak too when uh it's
subscriber only
uh auction stream lessons bidding with
channel points no
no channel police are worthless
unless you have seven thousand seven
million you can send one message
are you close to twitch partner
hopefully i mean it comes down to
whether they approve me or not
um if they don't approve me twitch is
telling me george hey we don't really
want your content around here
that's somewhere else you know uh you
guys all know where to find me
oh vips can't chat while subscriber only
that's sad
um
you guys will you know people who care
will find me somewhere else
people always manage to
uh
the elite can't speak i wish i wish we
could vip as we want
twitch i need more options twitch i need
more options
i'm not making a telegram chat well
vip's are the most butter subs i agree
with that
um cool
i mean look i'm thinking about this the
the
part of the college is to build the
online collaboration tools
uh not for people outside the school but
for people inside the school
where you have a real identity it's all
on the intranet
um
ironically google plus worked very well
inside of google
uh oh i guess i can yeah if i can give
subs to vips i could do that
i don't know if i can give subs can i
give subs
see roxas brandon if i wanted to gift us
oh gift a sub oh i can
oh that's nice
train intelligent bots that quote
quality questions to drive higher
quality discussion well then
i mean it's just me discussing with a
bunch of machines and eventually we'll
get there
you guys know i want to be a girlfriend
but that's my dream right
um
i want to yeah i want to start a call i
don't know do i want to do anything in
the world
should i just be a degenerate is is it
worth it did you actually have any
control i don't know
um oh it costs me
five dollars to gift a sub and i get
back half
wait that's a joke i gotta pay my own
um we've dropped these strict iq tests
we don't say we're not going to say iq
it's i again i didn't realize oh
so it's just an entrance exam uh
the university is going to have an
entrance exam and everybody who gets
above a certain point
on the entrance exam is welcome to come
to the university
you also have to have taken uh
the sat but and have finished high
school
but just for uh just for notation
purposes
just just for uh you will not be judged
based on your gpa or sat score
we are interested in tracking those
metrics uh over time
uh it's in twitch's favorite and not
like see that's what i mean you're right
you're absolutely right it isn't
twitch's favorite do not let vips talk
in sub-only mode
and this is where these platforms are
hostile
to both users and streamers to keep you
in their gamified right
this is why like you know am i going to
go out of my way to not get banned from
twitch no if i get back from twitch i
get back from twitch
i don't care i don't really do this for
money
i do this for my entertainment and your
entertainment there's a million other
ways to be entertained on the internet
yeah geds ged is fine i don't even
finished high school i i guess
i don't really care about that but like
i want to i want to track these things i
want to know what
correlates to to to to high school gpa
what correlates to sat score
uh are you pretty sure vips can talk
cool
uh let's let's just can vips
talk in sub only mode twitch
uh oh cool yeah yeah no they can
great
um unfortunately i don't notice what
subject first stream solve complex
github tickets in a popular
module oh i was like that sounds like
real work man
uh that sounds like that sounds like uh
pay me
there's some stuff that requires a real
like
expensive kind of focus if i was gonna
do things like that i have a whole set
of projects that i work on off stream
um that aren't uh
and then honestly it's probably going to
be
most of the time spent understanding
what they want and understanding the
code base a tiny amount of time writing
code
and then a huge amount of time getting
it upstreamed oh you got to sign your
contributor license agreement
and so on and so forth
um
yeah there's been a lot of talking on
these streams lately doing a lot of
thinking what else is there to do
in new york we think
cool guys it's just three hours thank
you for watching today's stream
i don't know if it's going to be monday
tuesday or wednesday
um but we're going to try to have a test
uh
test test thank you all for watching
have a good night everybody